Rahul Rajan

Mb. +91-9873731737 · 4/2266-F, Gali No. 2, Bihari Colony, Shahdara, Delhi-110032 · r96rajan@gmail.com · www.linkedin.com/in/rahul96rajan · rahul96rajan.github.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A transitioning machine learning engineer having an experience of 1 year and 8 months in developing Test Automation scripts and ensuring the quality of the software products. Currently a student of Post Graduate Diploma in Artificial Intelligence at CDAC, Noida, India.

EDUCATION

Qualification	School/College	Board/University	Year	Percentage
PG Diploma	Centre for Development	CDAC	2020 - Feb	NA (ongoing)
(Artificial	of Advanced Computing,		2021	
Intelligence)	Noida			
B.Tech (CSE)	KCC Institute Of	A.K.T.U., U.P.	2014 - 2018	69.8 %
	Technology and			
	Management, Greater			
	Noida, U.P.			
Class 12	A.S.N. Sr. Sec. School,	C.B.S.E.	2014	72.7 %
	Mayur Vihar-1, Delhi.			
Class 10	Kerala Education Society	C.B.S.E.	2012	87.4 %
	Secondary School, Mayur			
	Vihar-3, Delhi.			

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer II - Test Automation - *QA InfoTech Software Services Private Limited, Noida Sector 68*June 2018 - Feb 2020

Projects - Salesforce | Client - Kaplan, Inc., Fort Lauderdale, Florida, USA [July 2019 - Feb 2020]

- Design and build automated test framework and test suites for test cycles.
- Set up Selenium grids on Virtual machines and integrate with Jenkins server.
- Provide feedback to product owners and test leads to improve existing automation approaches.
- Develop, execute and enhance TDD based automation using tools like Selenium, Java and other software test tools.
- Participate in daily scrums and sync up calls with clients and developers to verify and communicate enhancements suggested for the application or issues logged.

Projects - E-Learning Application | Client - Macmillan Learning, New York, USA [June 2018 - July 2019]

- Develop test cases and maintain them regularly, working with product owners, developers and other vendors.
- Identify E2E scenarios and prioritize automation tasks accordingly.
- Hands-on test planning, test development, testing and defect submission and tracking.
- Worked based on Agile methodology and attended different ceremonies like Sprint Planning meeting, Scrum, Backlog Grooming, Sprint Review and Retrospective.

INTERNSHIPS

Software Engineering Virtual Intern - *JPMorgan Chase & Co.*

Aug 2020 - Aug 2020

- Created an interface with a stock price data feed
- Used JPMorgan Chase frameworks and tools
- Display data visually for traders
- <u>Tools used:</u> Python, Typescript, Git

Data Analytics Consulting Virtual Intern - KPMG, Australia

May 2020 - May 2020

- Assessment of data quality and completeness in preparation for analysis.
- EDA and Preprocessing the data.
- Creating ML models on the training dataset and after testing, using this to predict the probability of scoring business opportunities from new customers list.
- Using the insights to target high-value customers based on customer demographics and attributes.
- Data Insights and Presentation: Using visualisations to present insights to the client
- <u>Tools used</u>: Python, NumPy, Pandas, Google Sheets, Scikit-Learn, Microsoft PowerBI

Analyst Intern - PVR Cinemas, DLF Corporate Park, Gurugram, Haryana

July 2017 - September 2017

- Design and develop Jasper Reports and templates from data retrieved from MySQL database.
- <u>Tools used</u>: Java, Jasper iReport, SQL

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Java, Javascript, R, C/C++
- Development API/Frameworks: Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Keras, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Selenium, TestNG, Postman.
- CI-CD: Jenkins
- Comfortable working in Microsoft Windows and Linux distributions.
- Excellent communication skills with a focus on team-building and product enhancement.

CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES

- <u>Machine Learning</u> by Andrew Ng, Stanford University (coursera)
- <u>Deep Learning Specialization (5 courses)</u> by Andrew Ng, deeplearning.ai (coursera)
- <u>Mathematics for Machine Learning Specialization (3 courses)</u> by Imperial College London (coursera)
- <u>Probability Theory, Statistics and Exploratory Data Analysis</u> by Higher School of Economics, National Research University, Russia (coursera)

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Indian Red Cross Society, Sansad Marg, Delhi - Non-Profit Organization

May 2016 - PRESENT

• Blood donor (specifically for individuals suffering with Thalassemia)

LANGUAGE COMPETENCIES

- English: Full Professional Proficiency (speaking, reading, writing)
- Hindi: Native/Bilingual Proficiency (speaking, reading, writing)
- Malayalam: Native/Bilingual Proficiency (speaking, reading, writing)
- **Tamil**: Limited working proficiency (speaking)